CHAPTER 20 I SHALL LIVE FOREVER— —AND EVER— —AND EVER!" But they were obliged to wait more
than a week because first there came some very windy days and then Colin was
threatened with a cold, which two things happening one after the other would no
doubt have thrown him into a rage but that there was so much careful and
mysterious planning to do and almost every day Dickon came in, if only for few
minutes, to talk about what was happening on the Moore and in the lanes and hedges
and on the borders of streams. The things he had to tell about
otter and badgers' and water rats houses, not to mention bird's nests and field
mice and their burrows, were enough to make you almost tremble with excitement
when you heard all the intimate details from an animal charmer and realized with
what thrilling eagerness and anxiety the whole busy underworld was working.
"They're same as us," said Dickon, "only they have to build their homes every year and
it keeps them so busy they fair scuffle to get him done." The most absorbing thing, however,
was the preparations to be made before Colin could be transported with sufficient secrecy to the
garden. No one must see the chair carriage and Dickon and Mary after they
turned a certain corner of the shrubbery and entered upon the walk outside the ivied
walls. As each day passed, Colin had become more and more fixed in his
feeling that the mystery surrounding the garden was one of its greatest charms.
Nothing must spoil that. No one must ever suspect that they had a
secret. People must think that he was simply going out with Mary and Dickon
because he liked them and did not object to their looking at him. They had long
and quite delightful talks about their route. They would go up this path and
down that one and cross the other and go round among the fountain flower beds as
if they were looking at the bedding out plants" the head gardener, Mr. Roach, had
been having arranged. That would seem such a rational thing to do that no one
would think it at all mysterious. They would turn into the shrubbery walks and lose themselves
until they came to the long walls.
It was almost as serious and elaborately thought out as the plans of march made
by great generals in time of war. Rumors of the new and curious things
which were occurring in the invalid's apartments had of course filtered
through the servants' hall into the stable yards and out among the gardeners,
but not withstanding this, Mr. Roach was startled one day when he received orders
from Master Collins's room to the effect that he must report himself in the
apartment know no outsider had ever seen, as the invalid himself desired to speak
to him. "Well, well," he said to himself as he hurriedly changed his coat, "what's to
do now? His Royal Highness that wasn't to be looked at calling up a man he's never
set eyes on." Mr. Roach was not without curiosity. He had never caught even a
glimpse of the boy and had heard a dozen exaggerated stories about his uncanny
look and ways and his insane tempers. The thing he had heard oftenest
was that he might die at any moment and there had been numerous fanciful
descriptions of a humped back and helpless limbs, given by people who had never seen
him. "Things are changing in this house, Mr.
Roach," said Mrs. Medlock, as she led him up the back staircase to the corridor onto
which opened the hitherto mysterious chamber. "Let's hope they changing for the
better, Mrs. Medlock," he answered. "They couldn't well change for
the worse," she continued; "and queer as it all is there's them as finds their
duties made a lot easier to stand up under. Don't you be surprised, Mr. Roach, if
you find yourself in the middle of a managerie and Martha sbe's Dickon more
at home than you or me could ever be." There really was a sort of Magic
about Dickon, as Mary always privately believed. When Mr. Roach heard his name he smiled quite
leniently. "He'd be at home in Buckingham Palace or at the bottom of a coal mine,"
he said. "And yet it's not impudence, either. He's just fine, is that lad." It was
perhaps well he had been prepared or he might have been startled. When the bedroom door was
opened a large crow, which seemed quite at home perched on the high back of a carven chair,
announced the entrance of a visitor by saying cor cor quite
loudly. In spite of Mrs. Medlock's warning, Mr. Roach only just escaped being
sufficiently undignified to jump backward. The young Raja was neither in
bed nor on his sofa. He was sitting in an armchair and a young lamb was standing
by him shaking its tail in feeding lamb fashion as Dickon knelt giving it milk
from its bottle. A squirrel was perched on dickens's bent back attentively
nibbling a nut. The little girl from India was sitting on a big foot stool looking
on. "Here is Mr. Roach, Master Colin," said Mrs.
Medlock. The young rajer turned and looked his ctor over— —at least that was
what the head gardener felt happened. "Oh, you are Roach, are you?" he said. "I sent for
you to give you some very very important orders." "Very good, sir," answered Roach,
wondering if he was to receive instructions to fell all the oaks in the
park or to transform the orchards into Water Gardens I am going out in my chair this
afternoon," said Colin. "If the fresh air agrees with me I may go out every day.
When I go, none of the gardeners are to be anywhere near the Long Walk by the
garden walls. No one is to be there.
I shall go out about 2:00 and everyone must keep away until I send word that
they may go back to their work." "Very good, sir," replied Mr. Roach, much
relieved to hear that the oaks might remain and that the orchards were
safe. "Mary," said Colin, turning to her, "what is that thing you say in India when you
have finished talking and want people to go?" "You say, 'You have my permission to go,'"
answered Mary. The Raja waved his hand.
"You have my permission to go, Roach," he said. "But, remember, this is very important
cor cor remarked the crow hely but not impolitely. "Very good, sir. Thank you, sir,"
said Mr. Roach, and Mrs. Medlock took him out of the room. Outside in the corridor,
being a rather good-natured man, he smiled and until he almost laughed. "My
word!" he said, "he's got a fine lordly way with him, hasn't he? You'd think he was a
whole Royal Family rolled into one— —Prince Consort and
all he protested Mrs. Medlock, "we've had to let him trample all over every one of
us ever since he had feet and he thinks that's what folks was born
for." "Perhaps he'll grow out of it, if he lives," suggested Mr. Roach.
"Well, there's one thing pretty sure," said Mrs. Medlock. "If he does live and that
Indian child stays here I'll warrant she teaches him that the whole orange does
not belong to him, as Susan sby says. And he'll be likely to find out the size of
his own quarter." Inside the room Colin was leaning back on his cushions. "It's all
safe now," he said. "And this afternoon I shall see it— —this afternoon I shall be in
it!" Dickon went back to the garden with his creatures and Mary stayed with Colin.
She did not think he looked tired but he was very quiet before their lunch came
and he was quiet while they were eating it. She wondered why and asked him about
it. "What big eyes you've got, Colin," she said. "When you are thinking they get as big as
sources What are you thinking about now?"
"I can't help thinking about what it will look like," he
answered. "The garden?" asked Mary. "The springtime," he said. "I was thinking that
I've really never seen it before. I scarcely ever went out and when I did go
I never looked at it. I didn't even think about
it." "I never saw it in India because there wasn't any," said
Mary. Shut in and morbid as his life had been, Colin had more imagination than she
had and at least he had spent a good deal of time looking at wonderful books and
pictures. "That morning when you ran in and said 'It's come! It's come!' you made me
feel quite queer. It sounded as if things were coming with a great procession and
big bursts and wafts of music I have a picture like it in one of my books—
—crowds of lovely people and children with garlands and branches with blossoms
on them everyone laughing and dancing and crowding and playing on pipes. That
was why I said, 'Perhaps we shall hear golden trumpets' and told you to throw open the
window." "How funny!" said Mary. "That's really just what it feels like. And if all the
flowers and leaves and green things and birds and wild creatures danced past at
once, what a crowd it would be! I'm sure they dance and sing and flute and that
would be the wafts of music." They both laughed but it was not
because the idea was laughable but because they both so liked
it. A little later the nurse made Colin ready. She noticed that instead of lying
like a log while his clothes were put on he sat up and made some efforts to help
himself, and he talked and laughed with Mary all the
time. "This is one of his good days, sir," she said to Dr. Craven, who dropped in to
inspect him. "He's in such good spirits that it makes him
stronger." "I'll call in again later in the afternoon, after he has come in," said Dr.
Craven. "I must see how the going out agrees with him. I wish," in a very low
voice, "that he would let you go with him." "I'd rather give up the case this
moment, sir then even stay here while it's suggested," answered the nurse with sudden
firmness. "I hadn't really decided to suggest it," said the doctor, with his slight
nervousness. "We'll try the experiment dickens's a lad I'd trust with a newborn
child." The strongest footman in the house carried Colin downstairs and put him in
his wheeled chair near which Dickon waited outside. After the manservant had
arranged his rugs and cushions the Raja waved his hand to him and to the
nurse. "You have my permission to go," he said, and they both disappeared quickly
and it must be confessed giggled when they were safely inside the
house. Dickon began to push the wheeled chair slowly and
steadily. Mistress Mary walked beside it and Colin leaned back and lifted his face to the
sky. The arch of it looked very high and the small snowy clouds seemed like white
birds floating on outspread wings below its crystal bless The wind swept in soft big breaths
down from the Moore and was strange with a wild clear scented
sweetness. Colin kept lifting his thin chest to draw it in, and his big eyes
looked as if it were they which were listening— —listening, instead of his
ears. "There are so many sounds of singing and humming and calling out," he said.
"What is that scent the puffs of wind bring?" "It's gors on the Moore that's
opening out," answered Dickon a the bees are at it wonderful
today Not a human creature was to be caught sight of in the paths they took.
In fact every gardener or gardener's lad had been witched away. But they wound in
and out among the shrubbery and out and round the fountain beds, following their
carefully planned route for the mere mysterious pleasure of it. But when at
last they turned into the Long Walk by the ivied walls the excited sense of an
approaching thrill made them, for some curious reason they could not have
explained, begin to speak in whispers. "This is it," breathed
Mary. "This is where I used to walk up and down and wonder and wonder." "Is it?" cried
Colin, and his eyes began to search the ivy with eager curiousness.
"But I can see nothing," he whispered. "There is no door." "That's what I thought," said
Mary. Then there was a lovely breathless silence and the chair wheeled
on. "That is the garden where Ben weather staff works," said Mary. "Is it?" said Colin. A
few yards more and Mary whispered again. "This is where the robin flew over
the wall," she said. "Is it?" cried Colin. "Oh!
I wish he'd come again!" "And that," said Mary with solemn
delight, pointing under a big lilac bush, "is where he perched on the little heap
of earth and showed me the key." Then Colin sat up. "Where? Where? There?" he cried,
and his eyes were as big as the wolfes in Red Riding Hood when Red Riding Hood
felt called upon to remark on them Dickens stood still and the wheeled chair stopped.
"And this," said Mary, stepping onto the bed close to the ivy, "is where I went to talk
to him when he chirped at me from the
top of the wall. And this is the ivy the
wind blew back," and she took hold of the hanging green
curtain. "Oh! is it— —is it!" gasped Colin. "And here is the handle, and here is the door
dickan push him in— —push him in quickly!"
And Dicken did it with one strong, steady, splendid push. But Colin had actually
dropped back against his cushions, even though he gasped with delight, and he had
covered his eyes with his hands and held them there shutting out everything until
they were inside and the chair stopped as if by magic and the door was
closed. Not till then did he take them away and look round and round and round
as Dickon and Mary had done. And over walls and earth and trees
and swinging sprays and tendrils the fair green veil of tender little leaves
had crept, and in the grass under the trees and the gray NS in the alcoves and
here and there everywhere were touches or splashes of gold and purple and white
and the trees were showing pink and snow above his head and there were fluttering
of wings and faint sweet pipes and humming and scents and scents. And the
sun fell warm upon his face like a hand with a lovely touch. And in wonder Mary
and Dickens stood and stared at him. He looked so strange and different because
a pink glow of color had actually crept all over him— —ivory face and neck and hands and
all. "I shall get well! I shall get well!" he cried out.
"Mary! Dickon! I shall get well! And I shall live forever and ever and
ever!" CHAPTER